<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>parenting without dignity</title><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/feeds/rascals.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/</id><updated>2015-08-17T21:41:45-07:00</updated><entry><title>It's our stop.</title><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/second-avenue.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-08-17T21:41:45-07:00</updated><author><name>Steven</name></author><id>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2015-08-17:second-avenue.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We took the kiddos to New York City for a few days. As a wise dad once
said, "vacation is another word for your kids not sleeping in new places."
While on the subway train, riding uptown, the conductor's voice boomed
out, "next stop, second avenue." Our youngest, almost three, replied, 
"next stop, fucking avenue!"&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rascals"></category><category term="cursing"></category></entry><entry><title>Idiot! Idiot over there!</title><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/idiot-over-there.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-09T21:49:03-07:00</updated><author><name>Steven</name></author><id>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-09:idiot-over-there.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have come to understand that the epithet of choice when baby mama is driving
the kids around is 'idiot!'  I only came to understand this when our two year
old started to say this around this house.  Perhaps because the context in which one
yells in a car is not clear to a backward-facing child, it probably seemed like
an appropriate interjection for common use: when you are feeling happy, or
want to say, 'hello'. So he has taken to yelling, "idiot! idiot over there!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was terribly amusing for me when I took the child to the local bodega
recently. He pointed to some random customer and said, 'idiot!' 
I pretended to be deaf.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rascals"></category><category term="cursing"></category></entry><entry><title>I love your hair.</title><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/i-love-your-hair.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-09T20:22:00-07:00</updated><author><name>Steven</name></author><id>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-09:i-love-your-hair.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our two year old has recently started to tell us, "I love you." As a parent,
this is the most rewarding thing you can hear from a small child ("I want
to go to sleep" is a distant second). All the sleepless nights, the tantrums
(yours and the kid's), the endless ebb and flow of chaos and cleaning, all
worth it when your kid tells you what you've been telling them since they 
were born. Perhaps you had doubts, maybe you were too grumpy once too often,
too short tempered, away at work too much, maybe the kid loves only mama.
But now all is forgiven, everything is all right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment only lasted a short while, however, as kiddo told us everything
else that he loved: the tree, those cars, that triangle, the 'poop sucker
truck' (long story: there are a lot of porta johns
in our neighborhood). He has since graduated to also telling us what he
loves about us: "I love your eyes", "I love your skin", "Love your hair",
"Love that" (pointing to a scar on mama). These confessions sound like
very awkward pickup lines, although they are imbued with a sincerity only
a two year old can muster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have taken this as a blessing, and am glad the kid noticed my hair.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rascals"></category><category term="mushy"></category></entry><entry><title>Have a spoon!</title><link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/have-a-spoon.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-10-07T22:42:58-07:00</updated><author><name>Steven</name></author><id>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-07:have-a-spoon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was walking with number two son on Haight street, as is our habit, when
kiddo finds a long handled spoon on the sidewalk. Compared to the usual
broken glass and other unsavory what-not, it seemed like a perfectly 
reasonable treasure. A few doors down, the little rascal ran to the open
window at Noc-Noc, threw the spoon in at two dudes, then ran away laughing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="rascals"></category><category term="out and about"></category></entry></feed>