<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>parenting without dignity</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/</link><description>am I wearing your napkin?</description><atom:link href="http://parenting-without-dignity.com/feeds/steven.rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 21:41:45 -0700</lastBuildDate><item><title>It's our stop.</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/second-avenue.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;We took the kiddos to New York City for a few days. As a wise dad once
said, "vacation is another word for your kids not sleeping in new places."
While on the subway train, riding uptown, the conductor's voice boomed
out, "next stop, second avenue." Our youngest, almost three, replied, 
"next stop, fucking avenue!"&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 21:41:45 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2015-08-17:second-avenue.html</guid><category>rascals</category><category>cursing</category></item><item><title>A Halloween Curse</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/halloween-curse.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;For Halloween this year, Otaro, our oldest, wanted to be a Tarantula. 
Younger brother Jiro, just over two, idolizes O, and volunteered he
would be a purple Tarantula. I obliged with the costumes. As is par
for the course, wandering around exercising candy arbitrage is hard
work, and the kids started to squawk. 
At one point, young Jiro scampered to a (thankfully vacant)
house stoop, and told me, "This is a fuckingshit, daddy! A fuckingshit!"&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 21:41:54 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-11-01:halloween-curse.html</guid><category>shame</category><category>cursing</category><category>rascals</category></item><item><title>Coal in a stocking was too good for you</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/coal-was-too-good.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Leading up to last Christmas, there was a stomach flu going around Otaro's
preschool. We heard horrible tales from other parents as it made the rounds
(the worst was the kid who puked on another family at &lt;em&gt;the Nutcracker&lt;/em&gt;).
Baby mama and I were just a bit too smug about having avoided this plague. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, as they say, whom Santa notices, he destroys. On Christmas night, an hour
or so after the children went to sleep, we heard a kind of coughing from their
room, and then a comically loud water spilling type sound. And so it began. I
was the only one to escape without actually vomiting (let us say I had other 
severe gastric consequences, and leave it at that), as the virus picked us off
one by one. Things were especially tricky with Jiro, who was 15 months old at
the time, and would give no real warning before puking: just walking along,
then spits out a bunch of water, takes no real notice, toddles along through
the vomit puddle, &lt;em&gt;etc.&lt;/em&gt; Cleaning up after a puking child while you are 
seriously nauseous is, I can attest, horrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game of viral telephone did not stop with the immediate family. My
father-in-law, in town for the holidays, took ill some
three days later, spending the whole night puking. The rest of us left the
apartment so he could get some sleep. It was a bit cold, and we were too
fragile to do much outdoors. So it was that we found ourselves at
Ikea. Imagine a family of dehydrated zombies wandering endlessly
through Ikea, with no visible purpose other than killing time. OK, I guess
that describes most people at Ikea, but in our case we were also contagious.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 21:35:36 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-20:coal-was-too-good.html</guid><category>horror</category><category>sickness</category></item><item><title>Kitler youth</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/kitler-youth.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I only feel comfortable posting this one because I am technically Jewish.
'Technically' because, under Jewish law, since my mother was raised with
two sets of dishes, I am one of the Chosen People, ignoring that I grew
up eating Cheerios on Passover, and thinking Hannukah was the most important
holiday. Some months ago we spent a morning with friends of the family
who are functional Jews. The father is also a bicycle enthusiast, as am I.
I decided to draw our four year old into a discussion of our cargo bike,
which was my midlife crisis Porsche substitute, with the other dad. 
Admittedly this was a bit of a boast, but that is the purpose of a midlife
crisis toy. I was to be upstaged, however.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As might be familiar to 
parents of toddlers, the child wanted no part of our conversation. Instead,
he started riffing on what I was saying, going off on tangents, and then
spouting nonsensical rhymes, which quickly devolved:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;Me: &amp;quot;Otaro, do you like bikes?&amp;quot;
Otaro: &amp;quot;Daddy faddy kaddy kaddy.&amp;quot;
Me: &amp;quot;Does that mean you like cargo bikes?&amp;quot;
Otaro: &amp;quot;Kikes.&amp;quot;
Me: (nervously) &amp;quot;No, _bikes_.&amp;quot;
Otaro: (sensing blood in the water) &amp;quot;Kikes. Kikes! Kikes! Kikes!&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I do not remember how I distracted the child from his stream of 
racial epithets, maybe I shoved some apple slices in his mouth.
I do distinctly remember that feeling of wanting the earth to open
up and swallow me.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 21:01:04 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-15:kitler-youth.html</guid><category>shame</category><category>cursing</category></item><item><title>Idiot! Idiot over there!</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/idiot-over-there.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I have come to understand that the epithet of choice when baby mama is driving
the kids around is 'idiot!'  I only came to understand this when our two year
old started to say this around this house.  Perhaps because the context in which one
yells in a car is not clear to a backward-facing child, it probably seemed like
an appropriate interjection for common use: when you are feeling happy, or
want to say, 'hello'. So he has taken to yelling, "idiot! idiot over there!"&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was terribly amusing for me when I took the child to the local bodega
recently. He pointed to some random customer and said, 'idiot!' 
I pretended to be deaf.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 21:49:03 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-09:idiot-over-there.html</guid><category>rascals</category><category>cursing</category></item><item><title>I love your hair.</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/i-love-your-hair.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Our two year old has recently started to tell us, "I love you." As a parent,
this is the most rewarding thing you can hear from a small child ("I want
to go to sleep" is a distant second). All the sleepless nights, the tantrums
(yours and the kid's), the endless ebb and flow of chaos and cleaning, all
worth it when your kid tells you what you've been telling them since they 
were born. Perhaps you had doubts, maybe you were too grumpy once too often,
too short tempered, away at work too much, maybe the kid loves only mama.
But now all is forgiven, everything is all right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moment only lasted a short while, however, as kiddo told us everything
else that he loved: the tree, those cars, that triangle, the 'poop sucker
truck' (long story: there are a lot of porta johns
in our neighborhood). He has since graduated to also telling us what he
loves about us: "I love your eyes", "I love your skin", "Love your hair",
"Love that" (pointing to a scar on mama). These confessions sound like
very awkward pickup lines, although they are imbued with a sincerity only
a two year old can muster. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have taken this as a blessing, and am glad the kid noticed my hair.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2014 20:22:00 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-09:i-love-your-hair.html</guid><category>rascals</category><category>mushy</category></item><item><title>Have a spoon!</title><link>http://parenting-without-dignity.com/have-a-spoon.html</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I was walking with number two son on Haight street, as is our habit, when
kiddo finds a long handled spoon on the sidewalk. Compared to the usual
broken glass and other unsavory what-not, it seemed like a perfectly 
reasonable treasure. A few doors down, the little rascal ran to the open
window at Noc-Noc, threw the spoon in at two dudes, then ran away laughing.&lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">Steven</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2014 22:42:58 -0700</pubDate><guid>tag:parenting-without-dignity.com,2014-10-07:have-a-spoon.html</guid><category>rascals</category><category>out and about</category></item></channel></rss>